本字幕由YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译： ztonyy  爱卿遛小鸟  艾丝凡  V羊羊  索普  sakura
时间轴:  小猫  子衿   海豚  后期:  、loved
■
校对:  爱吃屎的鱼   士也瓜   总监:   爱吃屎的鱼
《复仇》前情提要
Previously on Revenge
-当时沙滩上是否还有别人  -没有
- Was there someone else on that beach? - No
杰克手里有件会直接将他与
Jack's been sitting on a hoodie that
谋杀案联系起来的运动衫
directly links him to the murder.
把他引出去几个小时吧
Just try to get him out of there for a couple of hours.
那是什么  你运动衫上的是血迹吗
What's that? On your sweatshirt, is that blood?
你说要让李听凭你摆布时
When you said you were gonna use Lee as your pawn,
你果然不是在开玩笑啊
you weren't kidding.
将死
Checkmate.
如果我要死
If I'm going down,
我一定拉上你们给我陪葬
I'm taking you down with me.
丹尼尔  你脚上的监视器
Daniel, your ankle monitor--
警察  把手举起来  不许动
Police! Hands up. Don't move.
听说有人上吊自杀了
They're saying someone hanged himself.
还在遗言中承认了杀害泰勒的罪行
And confessed to killing tyler.
又有一个大卫・克拉克要处理了
We have another David Clarke-style situation.
那是康拉德的声音吗
Is that Conrad?
我爸爸是被格雷森家族给谋杀的
The Graysons murdered my father.
赦免是宽恕中最强有力的方式
Absolution is the most powerful form of forgiveness...
它冲破怀疑与责任  寻求彻底的宽恕
A full pardon from suspicion and accountability.
解放被剥夺的未来
It's the liberation of a stolen future.
大卫・克拉克
那个我父亲无法亲眼见证的未来
A future my father never lived to see.
赦免
Absolution...
对于那些杀害他的人只能是永不可知的怜悯
is a mercy that people who killed him will never know.
流浪汉李・莫伦
The timing of the confession
在监狱中自杀并认罪
and jailhouse suicide of drifter Lee Moran.
恰巧发生在被告方准备
Coming just hours before the defense
开庭辩护的几个小时前
was to present their case,
这使那些密切关注
has raised suspicions among those who are carefully watching
这场所谓世纪审判的人大为怀疑
what many are calling the new trial of the decade.
伊丽莎白・霍桑法官整个早上
Judge Elizabeth Hawthorne spent all morning in chambers
都在闭门和控辩双方对话
with the prosecution and defense teams.
现在年轻的亿万富翁丹尼尔・格雷森的命运
And now billionaire Daniel Grayson's fate
仍然悬而未决
hangs in the balance.
舆论认为格雷森的清白
And still, Grayson's innocence remains very much in question
仍存有很大的疑虑
in the court of public opinion.
静音
是啊  还用得着说吗
Yeah, I'll say.
如果格里森是幕后黑手的话
You know, if the Graysons are behind all this,
你必须要跟夏洛特保持距离
you're gonna have to steer clear of Charlotte.
就像你对阿曼达・克拉克那样吗
Like you did with Amanda Clarke?
夏洛特走上现在这条歪道
Charlotte's headed down a really bad path,
我也有不可推卸的责任
and I'm partly to blame.
没错
Well, exactly.
所以一旦格雷森们发现了你也脱不了关系
Now that the Graysons know that you lied on the stand,
天知道他们会怎么来对付你
there's no telling what they might do to you.
恐怖分子大卫・克拉克在巴罗监狱被杀
我来猜猜看
Let me guess.
你正忙着制定你的婚礼宾客名单呢
You're working on your wedding invite list.
看来救你未婚夫的计谋
Well, assuming your ploy to spring your fiance
成功了
actually works,
但怎么可能不成功 你可是艾米莉啊
but why wouldn't it? You're you.
这是当年跟我爸爸住一个
These are the names of the prisoners
监狱楼的犯人名单
from my father's cell block.
我已经找出了我爸爸被杀那天
I've identified everyone who was involved in the riots
所有参与了那场监狱暴乱的人
the day that my father was murdered.
接下来干什么呢
Now what?
把这份名单跟格雷森家寄出的
Cross-reference it with the
圣诞贺卡名单对照一下吗
Grayson christmas card list?
诺兰  你知道捅死我爸的人
Nolan, you know the man that stabbed my father
一直没有找到
was never identified.
康拉德可能给了他们家一笔钱
Conrad could have made payments to their families.
或者安排他由于表现良好提早释放
He could have arranged for early pardon for good behavior.
又一桩罪行掩盖吗
Another cover-up?
康拉德在电话里说
Conrad said on the phone,
"抱歉又得让你干这件事了"
"I'm sorry to put us in this position again."
如果他们杀了李来灭口的话
If they killed Lee to silence him,
极有可能他们当年也采取了
it's a very strong possibility
同样的方法来对付我爸爸
that they did the same to my father.
你这是要去哪儿
Where are you off to now?
我去看看夏洛特  我很担心她
I'm going to check on Charlotte. I'm worried about her.
这幅画其实也算不上是多米尼克的佳作
Well, it's not exactly Dominik's best work.
我倒是觉得看上去有点杂乱无章
Looks a little half-assed if you ask me.
这是幅未完成的作品
It's unfinished.
早知道你这么有受虐倾向的话
You know, if I'd known you were such a masochist,
我倒是很愿意往你的伤口上撒上这把盐
I'd have volunteered to rub this salt in your wounds myself.
别这样嘛
Oh, come on.
你平常不是巧舌如簧的吗
Where's the witty repartee?
在你这种精神折磨之下
If you're expecting me to reveal so much
如果你指望我会表现出一丝痛心
as a wince of pain at the hands of your emotional torture,
你真是做梦
you can forget it.
好吧
Well...
不得不说我有点失望呢
Color me disappointed.
别  康拉德
Don't be, Conrad.
当我选择反击时  你好日子就到头了
When I choose to react, you'll know it.
我不仅会让你对你做犯下的
And I guarantee that you'll not just regret
每一桩罪行后悔不已
each and every one of your petty little torments,
还会让你品尝到十倍于今日
but that the suffering you so glibly spread around
你所带来的痛苦
will come back at you tenfold.
夏洛特  我是艾米莉
Charlotte, it's Emily.
丹尼尔出什么事了吗
Has something happened with Daniel?
没  我们还在等结果
No. We're still waiting.
你还好吗
How are you?
我没事  进来吧
I'm all right. Come in.
这都是些什么
What's all this?
属于我的
My version of...
父女时光
father-daughter time.
我妈妈对于他闭口不提
My mom won't tell me anything about him,
大卫・克拉克  本土恐怖分子
这是所有我能在公开信息中找到关于他的了
So this is everything i could find on public record
还有一些则是私底下的
And some that isn't.
我在我妈首饰盒的夹层里
I found this hidden in the lining
找到了这张照片
of my mother's jewelry box.
你看看背面的日期
Look at the date.
2002年4月22日
April 22, 2002.
他正是在这一天去世的
The day he died.
她从哪儿来的这张照片
I wonder where she got this.
他看上去并不像个恶人对吗
He doesn't look like a monster, does he?
不像
No.
他看上去很害怕
He looks scared.
我也是这么认为的
That's what I think, too.
我得去上学了
I have to get to school.
无穷小盒里有一本日记不见了
There's a journal missing from the infinity box.
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
因为在他临死前的一张照片里
Because he's holding one in a picture
他正拿着那本日记
taken the day he died.
什么照片
What picture?
照片不是重点  诺兰
The photograph isn't the point, Nolan.
重点是那本日记
It's the journal and the fact
我爸因为信任你把那盒子整个都交给了你
that my father trusted you with the box first.
艾米
Ems...
我把你父亲托付给我的东西全都交给了你
I gave you everything that your father asked me to give you.
而且
I mean...
如果真有这东西的话  我干嘛瞒着你呢
Why would I hold something like that back from you?
我也不知道
I don't know.
还正想问问你呢
You tell me.
我一会儿再打给你
I'll call you right back.
我只是遵照你父亲的遗愿
I was only honoring your father's wishes.
你知道我听到你这么说有多恶心吗
Do you know how sick I am of hearing you say that?
我没有说谎  我发誓
It's the truth. I swear.
在他去世前的最后几个月
In the last few months of his life,
你父亲被吓坏了  变得偏执多疑所以
your father was paranoid and terrified and--
所以什么
And what?
所以他不希望在你心里留下这种印象
And he wouldn't have wanted you to remember him like that.
我向你的父亲承诺过会保护好他的遗物
I promised that I would protect your father's legacy,
而我也确实是这么去做的
and that's exactly what I've done.
从今以后  别再插手此事了  诺兰
From now on, you stay the hell out of this Nolan,
不然我发誓  我会保证你插手不了
or I swear to God, I will make sure that you do.
《复仇》第一季第十九集
"自我被捕那一刻起
"From the moment of my arrest,
就呆坐着  信任着
I sat stupid and trusting,
坚信一个受人操控的司法系统
believing in a system rigged against me
而始作俑者正是那些我曾称为朋友的人
by the people that I knew as friends
那时的生活至今早已模糊了"
in a life that I can no longer remember."
"我越接近真相
"The closer I get to the truth,
身边的窃窃私语就越响
the louder the whispered voices around me,
谋划着我的死刑
plotting my execution,
挑选着时机"
choosing the time."
"如今我知道  我受困于命运与自由的较量中"
"I now know that I'm trapped in a race between fate and freedom."
"无论哪一方获胜  我不会再次保持沉默"
"Whichever wins out, I won't go quietly, not again."
"C.M.明天会带证据来"
"C.M. Will come tomorrow with proof."
C.M.
C.M.?
"卡罗尔・米勒"
"Carole Miller".
搜索
讣告
卡罗尔・琳恩・米勒
2002年4月24日辞世
杰克  别担心
Jack, don't worry.
德克兰现在不是格雷森家的目标
Declan is barely a blip on the Graysons' radar at this point.
那艾米莉呢
What about Emily?
她知道自己将要嫁进怎样的家庭吗
Does she have any idea what she's about to marry into?
艾米莉现在可没心情
Well, Emily's not exactly in the mood
听任何格雷森家的负面新闻了
to absorb any more negative Grayson press right now...
尤其是从我这听到
Especially from me.
不过也许她会听你的
But maybe she would listen to you.
顺便一问  你外带杯吗
Do you have a to-go cup, by the way?
干什么  你要上哪去
Why? Where have you gotta be?
我不光只会卖萌
Well, contrary to popular belief,
哥还是有个跨国公司要经营
I do have a multinational company to run.
我过两天还要出差呢
I'm gonna be gone on business for a few days.
好了  再见  杰克
All right. Bye, Jack.
给我电话
Call me.
经济学的突击测验你没来
Missed a pop quiz in Econ.
供需原则
Laws of supply and demand.
我知道定义
I think I understand the concept.
最后一瓶了  夏洛特
Make this one last, Char.
我爸到时候会发现他的病历单丢失的
My dad's gonna start missing his scrip pad.
你可不是学校里唯一能搞到药的  亚当
You're not the only guy in school with connections, Adam.
但最好我是你唯一献身的
But I better be the only one you're giving it up to.
抱歉
Sorry.
糟糕的一天
Bad day.
你不能再翘课了
You gotta stop blowing off class.
大家都开始议论纷纷
People are starting to talk.
由得他们
Let them.
我哥的这场噩梦结束以后
I'll pull it together
我就会振作起来的
when this nightmare with my brother is over.
在那之前
Until then...
你看什么呢  码头老鼠
What are you staring at, wharf rat?
没什么
Nothing.
我们能谈谈吗
Can we talk?
不能
No.
我们走吧  亚当
Let's get outta here, Adam.
新仁光医院档案室
New Mercy Hospital, archives.
你好  我想问一下你们的工作时间
Hi there. I'm just wondering, uh, what are your hours?
周一到周五  早上七点至下午四点
7:00-4:00, Monday through Friday.
死亡证明
如果你需要病史档案的话
If you'd like to request a medical record,
我可以给你寄一份申请表
I can mail you a legal form.
不用了  我稍后会自己过去取
No, that's all right. I'll come in and get one later.
杰克
Jack.
进来吧
Come on in.
你怎么样
How are you?
其实这话应该我问你吧
Actually, that was gonna be my question to you.
你要喝什么吗
Can I get you something to drink?
不用了  谢谢
No, I'm fine. Thank you.
一定很不容易吧
It can't be easy,
坐等别人宣布丹尼尔的命运
waiting to hear about Daniel's fate.
的确很不容易
No. No, none of it's easy.
你以为有人亲手写下的认罪书
You'd think that a written confession by someone
足以让法官撤销指控了  但是
would be enough for the judge to drop the charges, but...
更别提他们找到的那件带血帽衫了
Not to mention the bloody hoodie they found in his possession.
真神奇啊
It's kind of amazing...
一切就这样迎刃而解了  你不觉得吗
The way it all worked out, don't you think?
什么意思
How do you mean?
就是
Just...
格雷森一家有权有势
The Graysons are very powerful people.
也许那些法庭外的抗议者并不无道理
Maybe the protesters aren't as far off as you might think.
杰克  丹尼尔没有杀泰勒
Jack, Daniel didn't kill Tyler.
我没说他杀了
I'm not saying that he did.
那你是什么意思
Then what are you saying?
我是说  在嫁进他们家之前
That there are some things you might want to think about
有些事你得三思
before marrying into that family.
艾米莉  我有些事要告诉你
Emily, there's something I need to tell you.
抱歉打断一下
Oh, excuse me.
你好
Hello.
他们撤消了所有指控
They dropped all charges.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
我马上就到
Okay, I'll be right there.
杰克  我
Jack, I'm...
听着像是好消息  你去接他吧
Sounds like good news. You should go get him.
抱歉  我不是故意
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to--
不  是我不对  我突然来访
No, no, I'm sorry. I practically ambushed you.
我们迟些再谈
We can talk later.
你有我的名片六个多月了
You've had my business card for over six months.
时间宝贵  麦高恩先生
Timing is everything, Mr. Mcgowen.
你已经将格雷森国际的股票套了现
And now that you've cashed out your shares of Grayson Global,
我是不是可以认为
is it safe to assume
你已经万事俱备了
that the stars are properly aligned for you?
差不多吧
Nearly.
我要求完全豁免权
I want full immunity in exchange
以换取我将要告诉你的信息
for the information I'm about to give you.
在搞清楚我们要说什么之前
I can't guarantee anything
我无法保证任何事
till I know what we're talking about.
若你无法给予我保护
If you can't offer me protection,
我更愿意去和你证交会的上司谈
I'm more than happy to go to your superiors at the S.E.C.,
或者联邦调查局  中央情报局
or to the director of the FBI, the CIA,
或是其他任何有权定罪
or any other agency who would like to lay claim
国内恐怖分子的机构
to the conviction of a domestic terrorist.
恐怖分子
A terrorist?
我还以为你要揭露
I thought you had information
你丈夫公司的不法行为
about your husband's corporate malfeasance.
如此看来  麦高恩先生  这两样是同一件事
In this case, Mr. Mcgowen, they're one and the same.
我们达成一致了吗
Now do we have a deal or not?
让我打个电话
Let me make a phone call.
丹尼尔
Daniel.
凶手  凶手  凶手
Murderer! Murderer! Murderer!
凶手
你真的没事吗
You sure you're all right?
你几乎一言不发
You've barely said two words.
很遗憾你的车成了这样
Sorry about your car.
这事会逐渐平息的
This will eventually die down.
会没事的
It's gonna be okay.
恭喜  儿子
Congratulations, son.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
欢迎回家  丹尼尔
Welcome home, Daniel.
丹尼尔
Daniel.
谢天谢地总算结束了
Thank God it's finally over.
离结束还早着呢
No, this is a long way from over.
丹尼尔有些吓到了
Daniel's a little shaken.
监狱外有人在我车上喷漆
Somebody spray painted "Murderer" on my car
留下"凶手"两字
outside of the prison.
太可怕了
That's horrible.
是啊  媒体都快把监狱门给拆了
Yeah, the press were practically handing out pitchforks at the gate.
他说的一点也不夸张
He's not far off.
《时代》杂志在质疑
"The times" are questioning
认罪的真实性
the veracity of the confession,
八卦版用了一整版来历数
"Page Six" is running a full-page chronicle
丹尼尔过去不务正业的行径
of Daniel's past party-boy ways,
特德韦尔的"反格雷森"博客
and Treadwell's anti-Grayson blog
被各大主流媒体争相转载
is being rerun in every major newspaper.
这事情一时半会平息不了
This story isn't dying down any time soon.
我们不会让他们挖到新闻的
Well, then we'll starve the beast.
丹尼尔问心无愧
Daniel has nothing to hide.
我认为他现在最好的选择就是
I think the best thing for him to do
直面媒体  说出事情的真相
would be to get in front of the cameras, tell his story.
她说的对
She's right.
进攻是最好的防御
The best way to hit this is head-on.
所有主流媒体
Well, all the majors
可都在门口堵着呢
are practically banging down the door--
例如《晚间报道》  《早安美国》
"Nightline," "Good Morning America."
任由我们选
We can have our pick.
我两天都没合过眼了
Listen, I haven't slept in over 48 hours.
我现在无法清醒地做决定
I-I can't make that decision right now.
我去歇一会儿  好吗
I'm gonna crash for a while, okay?
当然  你得好好休息一下
Yeah, of course. You need some rest.
帮我转告夏洛特
Someone tell Charlotte
等我醒来后  再去好好拥抱她
I'll give her a big hug when I wake up.
做个好梦  亲爱的
Sweet dreams, darling.
你该好好地睡一觉了
You deserve them.
维多利亚  我能占用点时间和你谈谈吗
Victoria, could I talk with you for a moment?
当然
Of course.
那我们明天再见吧
I guess I'll see you all tomorrow.
好的
Yes.
怎么了  阿什莉
What is it, Ashley?
既然丹尼尔已经被释放了
Now that Daniel's been officially released,
我想正式提出辞职
I'd like to formally give my notice.
理所当然
Of course.
在你充分展现自己其他才能后
I had no delusions that you would return to party planning
我没有奢望你会委身重返派对策划岗位
after you so aptly showcased your other talents.
遗憾的是  我没足够的时间
Unfortunately, I won't have time
找个合适的接任者了
to find you a suitable replacement.
不用麻烦了
Oh, that won't be necessary.
汉普顿多得是
The Hamptons are filthy
你这样野心勃勃的小丫头
with ambitious young girls like yourself.
我能问一下你要去哪里高就吗
May I ask where you've landed?
布鲁克斯先生帮我在他的律师事务所里
Mr. Brooks has offered me a media relations position
找了个媒体相关的工作
at his law firm.
原来如此
Ah, well...
既然布鲁克斯先生还在为我们工作
As Mr. Brooks is still on retainer to us,
我想请你帮我个忙
I would like to ask you a favor.
如果丹尼尔真的错听建议  接受访谈
If Daniel does indeed grant this ill-advised interview,
我希望你能随时向我们通报媒体进展
I would like you to remain as our media liaison
直到一切平息为止
until it's over.
丹尼尔为我做过那么多事
That's the least I can do for Daniel
这点小忙我还是能帮的
after all he's done for me.
卡罗尔・米勒
治疗医师
莱尔・詹姆森
我是莱尔・詹姆森
Lyle Jameson.
你好  医生
Doctor, uh,
我是新仁光医院的伊芙・特科
this is Eve Tucker at New Mercy Hospital.
我们正在升级系统
We're updating our system,
有一名我们两家医院共同的患者
and I needed to cross-check our records
在认定其死因前  我需要再向您核准一下
before confirming cause of death of a patient we shared.
死者叫卡罗尔・米勒
Her name is Carole Miller.
我想我不记得有这个人
I'm afraid I don't recognize the name.
可能是事隔太久了
Perhaps it's because it's been a long time.
她2002年死于我们医院
She died here in 2002,
根据档案记录  您是
but it has you listed
她在兰开斯特的家庭医生
as her primary care physician in Lancaster.
她身高五英尺五英寸
Um... 5'5",
生于1950年
born in 1950,
患有二型糖尿病
type 2 diabetic.
有名叫卡罗尔・托马斯的病人符合你的描述
I have a Carole Thomas matching that description,
但她仍然健康地活着
but she's alive and well.
肯定是笔误了
That must have been a clerical error.
没错
Yes, it must have been.
谢谢你
Thank you.
宾州  兰开斯特
请问找谁
Can I help you?
你是卡罗尔・米勒吗
Carole Miller?
你找错人了
You have the wrong house.
我想我没走错  米勒夫人
I don't think so, Ms. Miller.
我是艾莉森・罗德尼
Alison Rodner from
在国土安全部工作
the department of Homeland Security.
我想和你谈谈康拉德・格雷森的事
I need to talk to you about Conrad Grayson.
你在格雷森国际
You worked for Grayson Global
给康拉德・格雷森做了18年的私人助理
as Conrad Grayson's personal secretary for 18 years,
我说的没错吧
is that right?
你明显知道答案了
Well, you obviously know the answer to that
否则你就不会来这里了
or you wouldn't be here.
那好吧
All right then.
你和大卫・克拉克
What was the nature of your relationship
有什么关系
with David Clarke?
没有任何关系
There was no relationship.
他替格雷森先生工作  不是替我工作
He worked for Mr. Grayson, not me.
那他因为197航班袭击案而被判刑
Were you surprised to hear that he was convicted
你感到震惊吗
for the downing of flight 197?
谁都没预料到会发生这种事
No one saw that coming.
可你料到了  对吗
But you did, didn't you?
茶里要加糖吗
Um, do you take sugar with your tea?
不用了
No.
现在
Now...
让我再看一下你的证件
Let me see that I.D. of yours again,
看看你是不是你所说的身份
and let's verify that you are who you say you are.
别  别  别  别
No, no, no, no.
卡罗尔阿姨
Aunt Carole,
把抢放下
just... Put down the gun.
卡罗尔阿姨
Aunt Carole?
这到底是怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
卡罗尔阿姨  这位是
Aunt Carole, meet, uh...
阿曼达・克拉克
Amanda Clarke,
大卫・克拉克的女儿
David Clarke's daughter.
我从麻省理工辍学后
Look, after I dropped out of M.I.T.
我老爸就把我踢出了家门
and my old man kicked me to the curb,
卡罗尔阿姨收留了我
aunt Carole took me in.
是她把我介绍给了你爸爸
She was the one that introduced me to your dad.
而你却背叛了他
And then you betrayed him.
不  她没有
No, she didn't.
她一直站在他那边
She was always on his side.
诺兰来找我
Nolan came to me
告诉我  他与狱中的大卫
and told me he had formed a bond with David
建立了联系
while he was in prison
他相信你父亲是被陷害的
and that he believed that your father had been set up.
于是我开始从格雷森国际内部
So I started investigating Grayson Global
开始调查
from the inside out,
我从而认识了一个叫罗杰・霍尔斯特德的人
and that led me to a man named Roger Halsted.
格雷森的高级会计
Grayson's senior accountant.
是的  是他
Yes, he's the one
发现了能把康拉德和恐怖分子联系起来的
that discovered the discrepancies in the books
账目出入之处
that connected Conrad to the terrorists.
我知道他是谁
Yeah, I know who he is.
他以为他手中的证据足以击垮康拉德
He thought he had enough evidence to hang Conrad
还你父亲一个清白
and exonerate your father.
那你们怎么不提交证据呢
Then why didn't you?
我们一直没找到机会
We never got the chance.
当我去监狱告诉你父亲
When I went to the prison to tell your dad
卡罗尔的新发现时
what Carole had learned,
监狱已经进入一级防范禁闭状态
they were already in lockdown.
大卫刚刚被杀害了
David had just been killed.
卡罗尔  是我
Carole, it's me.
你现在要按我说的做
I need you to do exactly as I say.
站起来  从你的座位走开
Get up and walk away from your desk.
不要拿你的包
Do not take your purse.
假装你只是去走廊转转  快走
Just act like you're walking down the hall. Do it now!
-你吓到我了  -那就对了
- You're scaring me. - Good.
叫辆出租车
Get in a cab and take it
直接开到那年夏天我们去的地方
straight to that place we went that one summer,
那个养马的地方
with the horses.
别去你的公寓
Do not stop off at your apartment.
我会在目的地等你
I'll be waiting when you get there.
就这样
So...
他救了我的命
He saved my life.
然后假造了你的死亡证明
By faking your death.
跟她说说那个白发人的事
Tell her about the white-haired man.
那时有个人
There was a man who
多次拜访过格雷森
visited Grayson a handful of times.
这些会面从不允许记录
Now these meetings were always off the books.
我第一次见到那个人
The first time I saw him
是在飞机遇难前的那一年
was a year to the day before that plane went down.
最后一次
The last time
则是在你父亲去世的那天早上
was the morning your father died.
你还记得他的名字吗
Do you remember his name?
他没有透露过
He never gave it.
但我永远忘不掉那张脸
But I will never forget his face.
他有满头白发
He had a full head of white hair
一双冰冷的蓝眼睛
and ice-blue eyes,
周身散发着令人不寒而栗的气息
and there was something so terrifying about him.
光天白日之下  他竟也能让康拉德畏惧
And I know he frightened Conrad even in the bright of day.
艾米
Ems...
真抱歉
I'm sorry.
但我不能把最后那本日记给你
But I could not give you that last journal.
对我来说  这比你报复格雷森
This is bigger to me than your revenge
更为重要
against the Graysons.
-这事关我的...  -家人
-  This is my-- - Family.
我理解
I know.
为了保护家人  我也会不惜代价的
I would've done anything to protect mine, too.
你来这有何贵干
What the hell are you doing here?
我是来把这个还给你
I wanted to give you this.
我的手机
My phone?
你从哪弄来的
How did you get this?
泰勒被杀那晚  我从他身上拿走的
I took it out of Tyler's jacket the night he was murdered.
什么
What?
是我在沙滩上  拖行了他的尸体
I'm the one who dragged his body up the beach.
也是你打晕了我吗
Are you also the one who hit me?
不是
No.
我没看到案发过程
And I didn't see what happened.
但我听到了枪声  赶到海边
I heard gunshots and I went to the water,
泰勒已经倒在那里了
and Tyler was lying there.
我以为那是你
I thought it was you,
然后我听到夏洛特和德克兰的声音
and then I heard Charlotte and Declan,
我慌了神
and I... I panicked.
既然你了解这些情况
Well, so much for your stand-up image,
还眼睁睁地看我被人冤枉
you were just gonna let 'em fry me?
我跟你说了
I told you,
我不知道是谁杀了泰勒
I don't know who killed Tyler.
但有一件事我很确定
But I do know one thing for certain--
在李・莫伦车里发现的那件带血帽衫
The bloody hoodie they found in Lee Moran's car
并不是他的
didn't belong to Lee Moran.
而是我的
It belonged to me.
我认为你父母
I think your parents
指使他潜入我家偷了那件帽衫
hired him to break in and steal it from me.
然后说服他承认罪行
And then what, convinced him to confess to the crime
自我了断吗
and hang himself?
你为什么要告诉我这些
Why are you telling me this?
因为艾米丽信任你
'Cause Emily trusts you.
如果她要与你共度此生
And if she's gonna spend her life with you,
为了她  你就不能无视这些事
you owe it to her not to ignore this.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你没有这个权利
You have no right.
你最好控制一下你的情绪
You might want to dial back on that indignation.
你的行为不仅违反了校规
You just violated the honor code,
还触犯了州法律
not to mention state law.
-你陷害我  -夏洛特  你需要帮助
- You set me up. - Charlotte, you need help.
你真可悲
You're pathetic!
如果我被学校开除了
If I'm getting kicked out of this school,
你也跑不掉
so are you.
我会让爸爸断了你下学期的学费
I'm telling my dad to pull your tuition next semester.
你玩完了
You're done here.
够了  走吧
That's enough. Come on.
别碰我
Don't touch me!
布鲁克斯先生
Mr. Brooks,
我以为您在这的工作已经结束了
I thought your work here was finished.
正在收尾
Nearly.
希望您不介意
I hope you're not upset that I agreed
我答应为格雷森家工作到
to stay and work with the Graysons
丹尼尔的电视访谈结束
through Daniel's television interview.
从后天起  我应该就可以
I should be able to start full-time
全心全意为您工作了
the day after tomorrow.
恐怕我不能
I'm afraid that offer
给你这个机会了  阿什莉
is no longer on the table, Ashley.
为什么
Why?
维多利亚提醒我  你颇有心机
Victoria warned me you were a little tricky,
于是我做了些调查
so I did some digging,
发现是你给媒体泄露了那些丹尼尔的照片
and I know you leaked those photos of Daniel to the press.
任何人处在我的位置都会这么做
I did what anyone would do.
不违反点规则  怎能从维多利亚・格雷森
You can't get beyond working for someone like Victoria Grayson
这种人手心里跳出去
without breaking a few rules.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我要花大把时间甄别客户的谎言
I waste enough time sifting through my clients' lies.
实在没兴趣再跟我的雇员玩这一套
I have no interest in doing the same with my employees.
格雷森家
Grayson.
联邦探员在这里  格雷森先生
The feds are here, Mr. Grayson.
联邦探员  他们想怎样
The feds? What do they want?
他们有搜查令  要进来全面搜查
They came with a warrant to seize everything.
全面搜查  这是什么意思
What do you mean, everything?
是谁批准的
By whose authority?
是美国人民批准的
By the authority of the people of the United States.
我是证交会的探员麦高恩  格雷森先生
This is agent McGowen of the S.E.C., Mr. Grayson.
我建议您明早留出时间
I suggest you set aside tomorrow morning
来一趟联邦大厦
to come down to the federal building
回答一些相关问题
and answer some questions.
您可能会需要律师随行
You're gonna want to bring your lawyer.
丹尼尔
Daniel.
我以为你还在家里休息呢
I thought you'd still be home sleeping.
我觉得我休息得够久了
I think I've been asleep long enough.
过来
Come here.
你还戴着它呢
You're still wearing it.
当然
Of course I am.
怎么  你反悔了
Why, are you having second thoughts?
我以为你会反悔
I thought you might be.
时过境迁了
So much has changed.
我不觉得
Not to me.
如果那些抗议的人是对的呢
What if those protesters were right?
如果我不该被释放呢
What if I didn't deserve that reprieve?
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
如果李・莫伦
What if Lee Moran
根本与泰勒的死无关呢
had nothing to do with Tyler's death?
我不懂你的意思
I don't understand.
一个胆大包天的职业罪犯
Why would a career criminal who's bold enough
又是勒索我父母  又是栽赃陷害我
to extort my parents and set me up for murder
怎么会突然良心发现呢
suddenly have a crisis of conscience?
谁知道呢  或许幡然悔悟了吧
I don't know. Maybe he finally realized he was in over his head.
或许吧
Maybe.
我决定接受明天那个访谈
I decided to do that interview tomorrow.
是吗
You did?
我真为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
父母把我当做格雷森家的顶梁柱来培养
My parents raised me to be a Grayson,
希望我有能力掌控一切
to put my name before everything,
包括真相
including the truth.
你不必这样勉强自己  丹尼尔
You don't need to be that guy, Daniel.
也许这次访谈是让你坦然面对一切的机会
Maybe this interview's an opportunity for you to be honest,
帮你脱离家族的光环
separate yourself from your name.
如果这能让你和父母之间产生
And if it creates a bit of healthy distance
一定的距离
from your parents,
那也是有益无害的
then all the better.
我去收拾行李
I'll go grab my stuff.
好
Okay.
还没睡吗
You're still up?
我以为你去艾米莉家了
I thought you'd gone to Emily's.
我回来拿东西
I came back to pick up my things,
看你灯还亮着
saw your light was on.
你还好吗
You all right?
不好
Uh, no.
我不是一般的
I am most definitely
糟
not all right.
很高兴你回来了
It's nice to have you back,
但我们家正处在
but our family is on the verge
灾难边缘  丹尼尔
of absolute catastrophe, Daniel.
我以房子打赌  前提是房子还归我所有
And I'd bet the house, if my name were still on it,
你妈和这事脱不了关系
that your mother has everything to do with that.
够了  爸爸
That's enough, dad.
我已经厌倦
I'm sick and tired of the two of you
你们之间的争斗了
playing me against the other.
可以理解
That's understandable.
在我们这段残破的婚姻中
You've been a pawn in our decrepit marriage
你一直就像个抵押品
for far too long.
我欠你一句道歉
I-I owe you an apology.
不  你欠我的是真相
No, what you owe me is the truth.
真相
The truth.
你知道为什么法官
Do you know why the judge
会如此慷慨  允许你家中软禁
so kindly granted you house arrest
而不是关在监狱受罪吗
instead of keeping you at Rikers?
知道  因为我差点被打死
Yeah, I nearly got beat to death.
你也知道是你妈雇人
And do you also know that your mother paid someone
安排了那次暴打吗
to arrange that beating?
李・莫伦
Lee Moran.
没错
Yeah.
他的认罪书不是真的  对吗
The confession he wrote wasn't real, was it?
不是真的
No.
告诉我  他不是你杀的
Tell me you didn't have him killed.
他知道的太多了
No, the kid was in too deep.
-爸  - 如果他把我们供出来
- Dad, come on. - If he'd started talking,
-我们都完蛋了  -我的天啊
- he would've destroyed us all. - Oh, come on.
我不能坐以待毙
I couldn't let that happen.
我只是保护我的家庭
I do what I need to do to protect the family.
一如既往
I always have.
你还做过什么
What did you do?
在我告诉你之前  你得向我保证一件事
Before I tell you, I need you to promise one thing...
如果最后我不幸获罪
That when they finally come to get me,
你要不惜一切重建公司
that you will do whatever you can to rebuild the company
并且照顾好你妹妹
and take care of your little sister.
我答应你
I promise.
你能去把门关上吗
Would you close the doors?
格雷森府邸  康拉德房间
要把这个故事讲清楚
In order for any of this to make sense,
我必须从一开始
I need to start at the beginning...
从我们对大卫・克拉克
With David Clarke
和他无辜的女儿所犯下罪行讲起
and what we did to him and his innocent baby girl.
夏洛特
Charlotte.
妈不管你想说什么  我都没时间听
Whatever you want, mom, I don't have time.
我上学快迟到了
I'm already late for school.
我刚和校长通过电话
I just got off the phone with the headmaster.
他告诉我 你被勒令停学了
He told me about the suspension.
我猜我们可以在格雷森家丑薄上
I guess we can add "Teen pill popper"
再添上一笔"少年毒瘾"
to the Grayson book of shame.
夏洛特  这没什么好笑的
This is no laughing matter, Charlotte.
你看见我笑了吗
Do you see me laughing?
我看得出你很痛苦
I see you in pain.
你拒我于千里之外  让我如何帮你呢
How can I help you if you don't let me?
我向你寻求过帮助  妈妈  你并不在意
I tried to let you, mom. You weren't interested.
不管你想找什么答案
Whatever answers you're looking for,
嗑药是没用的
you are not going to find them in a bottle of pills.
当然读这些垃圾
And you're not certainly not going to find them
也不能帮到你
reading this trash.
你从哪儿找到的这张照片
Where'd you get this?
我求你告诉我有关爸爸的事
I begged you to tell me about my father,
你断然拒绝
and you refused.
所以我只能自己去找
I had to go searching... on my own.
亲爱的
Oh, sweetheart.
这就是你嗑药的原因吗
Is this why you started taking drugs?
我不知道  妈妈  我微积分不合格
I don't know, mom. I'm failing calculus.
你自己算吧
You do the math.
气色不错
Looking good.
昨晚我好想你
I missed you last night.
对不起
I'm sorry. I...
我回到家后
I didn't realize how tired I still was
才感觉到自己有多累
until I got over here.
谢谢你如此善解人意
Thanks for being so understanding.
想好怎么应对
Have you thought any more about how you want to handle
这个访谈了吗
the interview?
满脑子都在想
It's all I can think about.
丹尼尔  我明白
Daniel, I know it's a lot.
你常说  你想做自己
You talk so much about wanting to be your own man--
要是我向往的自己不如我体内的遗传呢
What if the man I am is no better than my D.N.A.?
如实陈述真相将帮你从中解脱
Setting the record straight will help you break free from that.
如果你真的不想
If you truly don't want to follow
追随父母的脚步
in your parents' footsteps,
那就忠于自己的心
then don't.
刚才那话我当没听见
I'll try not to take offense at that remark.
我想跟儿子单独谈谈
A word with my son, please.
我在外面等你
I'll see you out there, okay?
现在我真是怀念
How I long for the days before Emily Thorne
艾米莉和她自以为是的愤慨
and her self-righteous indignation
未闯入我们生活之前的日子
became part of our daily lives.
不过她很快就会明白的
Well, she'll learn soon enough.
满口仁义道德的弊端在于
The downside of taking that kind of moral high ground
你有的是机会咬到自己的舌头
is that you have a lot farther to fall.
妈妈
Mom...
为什么法官会允许我家庭监禁
Why did the judge grant me house arrest
而不是把我关在监狱
rather than keep me in prison?
你的安全受到威胁  这你知道的
Your safety was at risk. You know that.
你和这事无关对吗
And you had nothing to do with it?
我的担心是对的
My suspicions were right.
你还没准备好面对媒体
You're not ready to talk to a reporter.
我去取消这次访谈
I'm going to cancel the interview.
我不会对你加以指责
I'm not gonna judge you.
我就想从你口中听到实情
Just tell me your side of the story.
是谁给你灌输了这些疯狂的想法
Who has been putting these crazy ideas into your head?
是艾米莉吗
Is it Emily?
你爸爸
Your father?
告诉我  他是一派胡言
Just tell me he's wrong.
抱歉打扰下
Sorry to interrupt.
丹尼尔  他们准备好了
Daniel, they're ready for you.
丹尼尔
So, Daniel,
48小时前  你在监狱
48 hours ago, you were in jail
面对一级谋杀的指控
facing a murder one charge.
现在你重获自由  感觉如何
Now you're a free man. How you doing?
比我48小时前好多了
A lot better than I was 48 hours ago.
再问一次
Just for the record,
是你杀了泰勒・巴罗吗
did you murder Tyler Barrol?
泰勒威胁我的家人
Tyler threatened my whole family.
为了争夺手枪  我俩扭打在一起
We struggled for control of the gun,
枪走火了
It went off, and...
接下来我只知道  我被杀手
The next thing I knew, I was knocked out
-打倒了  -就是李・莫伦
- by the guy who finished the job. - Lee Moran.
照他的认罪书来看  的确如此
According to his confession.
但事实是
But the truth is,
我完全不知当时在海滩
I'll never know Exactly what happened
李和泰勒之间到底发生了什么
between Lee and Tyler on that beach.
我只知道这个事件的结局
I only know how it ended.
昨天我从新闻上看到你被释放了
We saw your release from Rikers on the news yesterday.
"占领丹尼尔"现在成了推特热门词
"Occupy Daniel" was even trending on twitter.
对于公众的反应  甚至对你的恶意抨击
Are you surprised not only by the public reaction
你感到惊讶吗
but by the vitriol directed at you?
一方面  我很惊讶
On--on one hand, yes.
但另一方面  我表示理解
But on the other, I- I get it.
人们觉得自身权利受到损害
People feel disenfranchised and fed up
也受够了那些享特权的少数人
with the privileged minority
好像他们遵守的是自己定的一套规则
who seem to abide by their own set of rules.
如果有人犯了罪
Listen, if anyone commits a crime,
不论是谁
no matter who you are,
都该为此付出代价
he or she should pay for it.
说起这个...
Speaking of which...
证交会已经下令
The S.E.C. has issued an order of investigation
调查你的家族企业
of your family's company, Grayson Global,
你未来将继承的格雷森国际
a company you stand to inherit.
你对这些
Would you like to comment
贪污诈骗的指控作何看法
on the allegations of corruption and fraud?
我的父亲是这起莫须有调查的受害者
My father is the victim of a witch hunt.
证交会几个月来一直在骚扰我们的公司
The S.E.C. has been harassing my family's company for months
现在竟试图利用
and is now attempting to trade
公众对我的怀疑
on the mistrust the public has of me
而对公司提出毫无根据的指控
to build a baseless case against it.
我那案子  真相最终大白
In my case, the truth came out.
我父亲这次也会如此
The same will be true for my father...
我将以儿子的身份支持他
who I stand behind as a son
以工作伙伴的身份协助他
and beside as a partner in business
为以后领导格雷森国际做好准备
as I prepare for my role at Grayson Global.
我不知道该说什么
I hardly know what to say.
谢谢
Thank you.
这就是你的计划吗
So that's your plan,
回到格雷森国际工作
to go back to Grayson Global?
没人说我不能既做自己
Well, no one said I can't be my own man
又做我父亲的儿子
and be my father's son.
说的是
That you are.
丹尼尔  请你过来签下这个
Daniel, I need you to sign this.
亲爱的  穿好你的大衣
Sweetheart, get your coat.
怎么了  你要带我去哪里
Why? Where are you taking me?
离开之前都不说声再见吗
You're not leaving without saying good-bye.
再见  格雷森先生
Good-bye, Mr. Grayson.
那别忘了这个
Well, don't forget this...
你雷克萨斯车的钥匙
the key to your new Lexus GS.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你可以开着它永远地离开汉普顿
You can either drive this out of the Hamptons forever
也可以把它停在格雷森国际里你的新车位上
or you can drive it to your new parking space at Grayson Global.
我不能代表布鲁克斯
I can't speak for Brooks,
但我个人敬佩那些
but I for one admire someone who doesn't mind
不惜脏了自己手的人
getting her hands dirty.
只要你明白从现在起
As long as you understand that from this point forward,
我们可就是一条船上的人了
our hands will be intertwined.
那维多利亚怎么办
And what about Victoria?
维多利亚和你一样还没明白
What both you and Victoria have yet to grasp
她对任何人来说
is just how little she matters...
都不重要
to anyone.
不能再去上柯林斯预科学校了
so no more Collins prep.
是的  她让她爸撤走了我的学费
No, she told her dad to pull my tuition.
我什么都不能做
There's nothing I can do.
我倒是可以做点什么
There is something I can do.
诺兰  等等
Nolan, Nolan, wait.
别说了
No, stop.
杰克  我想这么做
Jack, I want to do this.
很久以前
Once upon a time ago,
我非常幸运
I was lucky enough to...
能在我最需要的时候获得他人的帮助
have someone take care of me when I needed it.
我非常感激
Look, I appreciate that,
但我们应该借此机会
but we should be taking this opportunity
摆脱格雷森一家
to get away from the Graysons.
没错
Exactly.
你说自己不愿让德克兰
You said you didn't want Declan
花格雷森家的钱去读柯林斯预科学校
to go to Collins prep on the Graysons' dime.
现在他不用了
So now he won't be.
但他理应像其他人那样
He still deserves an overpriced education
得到奢侈的高质量教育  不是吗
like everyone else, no?
巴里  我的老伙计...
Barry, my man...
我需要你给柯林斯预科学校
I need you to cut a check
开张支票
to Collins prep.
每当我回到这里
Every time I come back here,
顷刻涌出的回忆
my memories always rush back
将我带回听见他死讯的那一刻
to the moment I heard he died.
我最后悔的事便是...
And the first regret I had...
我没让他见过你
is how I held you from him.
他永远都没有机会  让你们彼此了解
He would never get a chance to know you or you him.
夏洛特  随便你怎么想我
You can despise me all you want, Charlotte,
但你的父亲
but your father...
他是个好人
he was a good man.
他犯了一个错误
He made one mistake
使自己陷入万劫不复的深渊
that led him down a path of destruction.
看来这是我们之间的共同点
I guess we have that in common.
你身上有太多与他相似之处
There are so many things about you
会唤起我对他的记忆
that remind me of him...
你的眼睛
Your eyes,
你的笑声
your laugh.
你爱我吗
Do you love me...
即使每次都是透过我  你都会想起他
even though every time you look at me, you think of him?
夏洛特  你还不懂吗
Charlotte, don't you get it?
正因如此  我才更加地爱你
It's because of that that I love you all the more.
妈妈  有人来过这里
Mom, somebody's been here.
艾米丽
Emily.
你还好吗
You okay?
我想喝杯酒
I could use a drink.
要点什么吗
Anything in particular?
老板说了算
Dealer's choice.
那我去后面拿好酒出来
I'll go get the good stuff from the back.
今天不太顺吗
Rough day at the office?
他变成一丘之貉了  诺兰
He's one of them, Nolan.
康拉德在采访前  向丹尼尔坦白了一切
Conrad confessed everything to Daniel before the interview.
所有的一切吗
"Everything" everything?
丹尼尔本可以讲出所有实情
Daniel could've come clean.
他本可以...
He could've...
结束一切的是是非非
ended the whole thing.
但相反...
But instead...
他和格雷森同流合污了
He doubled down on Grayson.
那现在你准备怎么办
So what are you gonna do now?
我准备嫁给他
I'm gonna marry him.
查出杀害我父亲的凶手
I'm gonna track down the man who killed my father.
找到他以后  你准备怎么办
And what are you gonna do when you find him?
杀了他
I'm gonna kill him.
赦免是洗净罪孽的圣水
Absolution is the washing away of sin...
是赋予重生的承诺
the promise of rebirth...
是先人逃脱罪责的机会
and the chance to escape the transgressions of those who came before us.
我们中的智者从过去吸取教训
The best among us will learn from the mistakes of the past,
然后余下的凡人注定重蹈覆辙
while the rest seem doomed to repeat them.
实际上
Well, the truth is,
我以前很欣赏大卫・克拉克
I always liked David Clarke.
他可靠  有效率  还很幽默
He was reliable, efficient, good-humored.
我想  他不留破绽地
I suppose the fact that
在这里与大家共事
he fit in so seamlessly around here
正是他如此危险的原因
is what made him so dangerous.
很抱歉  格雷森先生  但那人又来了
I'm sorry, Mr. Grayson, but that man's here again.
而且执意要见你
He won't take no for an answer.
今天就到这里吧  特德韦尔先生
That'll be all for today, Mr. Treadwell.
而那些游走于社会边缘之人
And then there are those who operate on the fringes of society...
会冲破道德的底线  卸下良知的包袱
unburdened by the confines or morality and conscience...
一种残忍的野兽
A ruthless breed of monsters
其最致命的武器是
whose deadliest weapon is their ability
在开阔的视野里隐藏自己
to hide in plain sight.
如果那些我要审判的罪人
If the people I've come to bring justice to
无意于寻求赦免
cannot be bound by the quest for absolution...
我亦不会手下留情
Then neither will I.